Guide to the Cornelius Eady Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Cornelius Eady Papers
1968-2012
JWJ MSS 146
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
38.96
(42 boxes)
The Cornelius Eady Papers contains writings, correspondence, printed material, electronic files, and audiovisual material that document the professional activities of African American poet, author, and educator Cornelius Eady.
Eady, Cornelius, 1954-
Scope and Contents
The Cornelius Eady Papers contain writings, correspondence, electronic records, audiovisual material, and printed material created and accumulated by American poet and educator Cornelius Eady, documenting his life and work as well as literary organizations including Cave Canem, and African American arts and letters broadly.
Arrangement
Not arranged in any particular order, as received by the Beinecke Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 37-40 (computer discs and audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 41 (Student evaluations): Restricted until 2094. Consult the appropriate curator for further information.
Cornelius Eady (1954-)
Cornelius Eady, American poet, born 1954. In 1996 he co-founded Cave Canem, a nonprofit organization dedicated to the cultivation of African American poets.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from James S. Jaffe Rare Books on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2013.
Scope and Contents
The Cornelius Eady Papers contains writings, correspondence, printed material, electronic files, and audiovisual material that document the professional activities of African American poet, author, and educator Cornelius Eady. Writings span the length of Eady's career from his first published book of poetry, Kartunes (West Orange, N.J.: Warthog Press, 1980), to the collection Hardheaded Weather (New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 2008). In addition to poetry, writings include numerous drafts and associated material documenting his collaborative works of musical theater: You Don't Miss Your Water, Running Man, Fangs, and Brutal Imagination.
Other papers in the collection document Eady's involvement in American arts and letters through his contributions to educational and professional organizations, especially Cave Canem, a nonprofit organization dedicated to the cultivation of African American poets. Correspondence and Writings of Others include numerous poetry manuscripts accumulated by Eady in the course of his activities as a teacher and mentor to other poets.
Related Materials
Cave Canem Records (JWJ MSS 130). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
African American poets; American poetry -- African American authors; American poetry -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 21st century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors, American -- 21st century; Authors, American -- 21st century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 21st century; Poets, American -- 21st century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 21st century; Born digital -- United States -- 20th Century; Born digital -- United States -- 21st century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 21st century; African American poets -- United States -- 20th Century; African American poets -- United States -- 21st century; Eady, Cornelius, 1954-; Cave Canem (Organization)
- "Writing the Medical Experience: A Workshop", 2007, undated (Box 1)
- "The Writer's Voice of Billings YMCA," grant application, 1992 (Box 1)
- Poems, 1980, undated; 8 (Box 1)
- Poems, undated; 1; reel to reel tapes (Box 37)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- Poems, undated; 1; reel to reel tapes (Box 37)
- Poems, undated; 1; reel to reel tapes (Box 37)
- "Dreaming in Hi-Fi," songs by Cornelius Eady, 1996; 1 compact disc (Box 40)
- Contract, 1980 (Box 1)
- Printed material, undated; 2 (Box 1)
- Business cards, undated (Box 1)
- "The Shirt Off Your Back," biographies, pictures, and tentative orders (mailing list), undated (Box 1)
- Writings sent to Sarah Micklem by M. Wilber, 1981 (Box 1)
- "Kartunes," worksheets and proof, undated (Box 1)
- "The War Against The Obvious: New and Selected Poems by Cornelius Eady", undated; 2 (Box 1)
- "Lucky House: Poems on a New House", undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1980-1984, undated; 2 (Box 1)
- Poems, drafts, mostly from Kartunes and The Modern World, undated; 2 (Box 1)
- Envelopes, undated (Box 2)
- Poems of others (photocopies), undated (Box 2)
- Cornelius Eady, Kurt Lamkin, and Brickyard, undated; 1 (Box 37)
- "Passing into Dawn," by Matthew Fox, undated (Box 2)
- "Every room we ever slept in," poems by Jason Shinder, undated (Box 2)
- Poems of Lewis A. Brunnemer, undated (Box 2)
- Newsletters, 1989-1993 (Box 2)
- Poetry Center Publicity, 1986-1990 (Box 2)
- "You Don't Miss Water," working draft, 1995 (Box 2)
- Unsorted papers, 1990s; 7 (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes correspondence, notes, ephemera, records of boards, organizations, and grant programs that Eady was involved in (including the National Writers' Voice Project and the National Endowment for the Humanities), and papers relating to Stony Brook University.
- Photographs, 1980s-2000s; 2 (Box 3)
- Reading, Interview VA writers, undated; 1 (Box 37)
- Eady NPR feature, 1992 November 26; 1 (Box 37)
- Poem, The Writers Almanac, 1995 May 1; 1 (Box 37)
- Poetry Radio tape 4, undated; 1 (Box 37)
- NPR Eady Interview, 2001 February 11; 1 (Box 37)
- Poetry music spots with Eady, Murray, and Hwang, 1997 March 31; 1 (Box 37)
- Cornelius Eady: "Dangerous Times", 1990; 1 (Box 37)
- "Graditude" Thanksgiving NPR, 1992 November 26; 1 (Box 37)
- Cave Canem African American Writer's Group, St. Mark's Poetry Project, 2003 March 14; 3 compact discs (Box 40)
- Kinship (You Don't Miss Your Water), working draft, 1990s (Box 3)
- Running Man scripts, poems, drafts, Cave Canem Foundation proposals, undated; 8 3.5' floppy disks (Box 40)
- Brutal Imagination, reviews, 1999-2002 (Box 3)
- Brutal Imagination and Running Man, related material, 1997-2002; 6 (Box 3)
- National Book Awards, photographs and letter, 2002 (Box 3)
- Poems by Kari Nelson, 1987 (Box 3)
- "Coda: Poets & Writers Newsletter", 1976-1980 (Box 3)
- Unsorted papers, including correspondence, clippings, and curriculum vitae of Cornelius Eady, 1980s (Box 3)
- The PEN Scratch Zone, 1985 (Box 4)
- Personal papers including warranties, car registration, undated (Box 4)
- "Against It," worksheets, undated (Box 4)
- Poems, undated; 4 (Box 4)
- MFA Program application, 1985 (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1987-1990; 2 (Box 4)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence, poems of Cornelius Eady and others, clippings, and organizational records, undated; 8 (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1995-2000; 6 (Box 5)
- Rona Jaffe Award
  - Committee meeting, 1997 April 24 (Box 5)
  - Alejandro, Ann, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Anapol, Bay, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Patrinos, Angela, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Lee, Rebecca, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Packer, ZZ, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Jeffers, Honoree, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Perry, Alice, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Bolus, Julia, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Bender, Karen, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Williams, Waimea, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Watson, Ellen, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Vazirani, Reetika, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Wren, Celia, undated (Box 5)
  - Sikelianos, Eleni, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Winters, Anne, 1997; 2 (Box 5)
  - Santos, Marisa de los, 1997 (Box 5)
- Clippings, Borders Books press release, 1995 (Box 5)
- Poems by Shawn Parsons, undated (Box 5)
- Printed material, 1990s (Box 5)
- Poetry in the Branches: The Model, 1990s (Box 5)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence and notes, undated; 2 (Box 5)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence, writings, and printed material, 1990s; 4 (Box 6)
- Computer disks: Stony Brook text, Ralphie, Zanzibar, undated; 3 3.5" floppy disks (Box 40)
- Tender, by Toi Dericotte, 1997 (Box 6)
- Autobiography of a jukebox, proof with manuscript corrections, undated (Box 6)
- Plaque presented to Cornelius Eady at the Annual Humanities Festival, Tougaloo College, 1993 March (Box 6)
- Poems, undated; 6 (Box 6)
- Victims of the Latest Dance Craze, undated (Box 6)
- Poems, "Papers on the desktop", undated (Box 6)
- Clippings, undated (Box 6)
- Printed material, including publications of Poets in the Schools, Arts and Humanities Center, Richmond Public Schools, 1980s (Box 6)
- Notes, undated (Box 6)
- Cornelius Eady letterhead, undated (Box 6)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence, printed material, and curriculum vita of Cornelius Eady, 1970s-1980s; 4 (Box 6)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence, notes, and printed material, undated; 4 (Box 7)
- "Prison", undated (Box 7)
- "Little Pond", undated (Box 7)
- Correspondence, 1974-1989; 7 (Box 7)
- "I Want to be a Baker", undated; 1 (Box 37)
- "Dull Strings and Catawailing II", undated; 1 (Box 37)
- "Childs Play", undated; 1 (Box 37)
- "Nothing," "Youngbloods," "Dull Strings and Catawailings", undated; 3 audiocassettes (Box 37)
- "Youngbloods", undated; 1 (Box 37)
- "Dull Strings and Catawailings", undated; 1 (Box 37)
- Unlabeled cassette, undated; 1 (Box 37)
- "Corny Eady and Jay Goodspeed", 1973; 1 (Box 37)
- "Practise Tape", undated; 1 (Box 37)
- "C & S", 1980, undated; 1 (Box 37)
- "Cornelius Eady- Harvard University, Afro-American Resource Center", 1980 September 29; 1 (Box 37)
- "Things No One Else Hears", undated; 1 (Box 37)
- "The Lean Cuts", undated; 1 (Box 37)
- "Poems by Cornelius Eady", undated; 1 (Box 37)
- "Barb Bery", undated; 1 (Box 37)
- Back up disks, undated; 10 3.5' floppy disks (Box 40)
- Unsorted papers including writings of others, printed material, financial records, and correspondence, 1968-1976; 2 (Box 8)
- Photographs of Cornelius Eady, 1980s (Box 8)
- Copyright information, undated (Box 8)
- Poems, 1970s; 4 (Box 8)
- Kartunes, undated (Box 8)
- Poems and sketches, undated (Box 8)
- Learning to float (Box 8)
- Sweet Briar College, 1982 (Box 8)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence, printed material, and writings, undated; 3 (Box 8)
- Printed material, 1994-1996; 10 (Box 9)
- Correspondence, 1994-1996; 2 (Box 9)
- Correspondence, 1994-1996; 3 (Box 10)
- Debt collector with wings: Uncollected poems 1980-1985, undated (Box 10)
- The modern world, undated (Box 10)
- Poems, 1990s; 6 (Box 10)
- Photograph of an infant, with later reproductions, circa 1990s, undated (Box 10)
- An interview with Cornelius Eady, by Charles H. Rowell, 1990 (Box 10)
- You don't miss your water, poems by Cornelius Eady, 1990s (Box 10)
- Poems, undated; 3 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, 1994-1996; 3 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, 1994-1996; 3 (Box 11)
- Unsorted papers including printed material, correspondence, and poems, 1994-1996; 9 (Box 11)
- Photographs of Cornelius Eady, undated; 2 (Box 12)
- Dangerous times, lyrics, undated (Box 12)
- Poetry chapbooks, 1980s (Box 12)
- Poems, undated; 3 (Box 12)
- Correspondence, 1991-1993; 3 (Box 12)
- Ephemera, including schedules, broadsides, publicity material, and printed material, 1990-1995; 9 (Box 12)
- The New York Times, 1991 October 17 (Box 36 (Oversize))
- Applications for National Book Foundation Summer Writing Camp, 1998; 2 (Box 13)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence, writings of others, and printed material, undated; 7 (Box 13)
- Advertisement for Manhattan Mini Storage, 1998 (Box 36 (Oversize))
- Correspondence, circa 1998; 3 (Box 13)
- Jenny McKean Moore, poetry related to the theme of Ferris wheels, 1999 (Box 14)
- The Running Man poems, undated (Box 14)
- Poems, including poems of others, undated; 5 (Box 14)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence, ephemera, printed material, and poems of others, 1990s; 4 (Box 14)
- Correspondence, 1998; 2 (Box 14)
- Running Man, 1998; 2 (Box 14)
- Poems, circa 1998 (Box 14)
- The Secret Woman, by Rose Solari, 1998 (Box 14)
- Running Man, circa 1998; 6 (Box 15)
- Poems from the Running Man, circa 1998; 2 (Box 15)
- Words for breakfast: A collection of prose and poetry from The National Book Foundation's 1996 and 1997 summer writing camps, circa 1997 (Box 15)
- An autobiography for those forced to fight the sun, by Kambui Olujimi, undated (Box 15)
- Fangs, 2000 (Box 15)
- Writings, including poems of others, undated (Box 15)
- Unsorted papers including pamphlets, newsletters, catalogs, promotional material, grant applications, and writings of others, 1997-2007; 5 (Box 15)
- Correspondence, 1997-2006; 6 (Box 16)
- Love that dog, a novel by Sharon Creech, 2006 (Box 16)
- Canals, by Myron Hardy, undated (Box 16)
- Purpose of MY writing poetry, by Gimbiya Kettering, 2004 (Box 16)
- Telling the beads, sonnets by M. S. Montgomery, 1994 (Box 16)
- Poems, undated (Box 16)
- "Skirt Full of Black" by Sun Yung Shin, 2006 (Box 16)
- "Kiss the Sky" edited by Richard Peabody, 2006; 6 (Box 16)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence, clippings, programs, and writings of others, 1990-1995; 5 (Box 17)
- Poems, 1990s; 6 (Box 17)
- River and bridge, poems by Meena Alexander, 1996 (Box 17)
- Proposal to the McGraw Hill Foundation, 1997 (Box 17)
- Transcript of an interview with Cornelius Eady by Eugene Redmond, 1993 (Box 17)
- Kinship, undated (Box 17)
- Correspondence, 1990-1995; 4 (Box 17)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence, notes, and printed material, 1990-1995; 4; (includes 2 audio compact discs) (Box 18)
- Printed material, 1994-1998; 2 (Box 18)
- You gotta earn it: The iconography of the blues as a literary device in the poetry of Langston Hughes, Etheridge Knight, and Cornelius Eady, 1998 (Box 18)
- Walking back up depot street, by Minnie Bruce Pratt, 1998 (Box 18)
- Poems, undated (Box 18)
- Running Man, circa 1998; 2 (Box 18)
- Poems by G. E. Patterson, circa 1998 (Box 18)
- Running Man, circa 1998; 2 (Box 19)
- The Gospel of barbecue, by Honorée Fanonne Jeffers, 1998 (Box 19)
- The water between us, poems by Sara McCallum, 1998 (Box 19)
- Femme du monde, a collection of poetry, by Patricia Kay Spears Jones, 1998 (Box 19)
- Poems by Robin LaNelle Dunn, 1998 (Box 19)
- Poems, undated; 2 (Box 19)
- Pagan operetta, by Carl Hancock Rux, 1998 (Box 19)
- Correspondence, undated; 4 (Box 19)
- Fangs, undated (Box 19)
- "You Don't Miss Water", undated (Box 19)
- "The War Against the Obvious", undated (Box 19)
- "Ota's Song (Stories for my brothers) and Other Poems" by Carrie Allen McCray, undated (Box 19)
- Running Man, 1998 (Box 19)
- Poems, 2001 (Box 19)
- Correspondence, circa 2001 (Box 19)
- Poems, undated (Box 20)
- Correspondence, 1994-1997; 2 (Box 20)
- Unsorted papers including printed material, correspondence, and notes, 1995-1996; 7 (Box 20)
- Correspondence, 1995-1996; 4 (Box 20)
- Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 21)
- Three books, by Nora Wright-Goldin, 1995 (Box 21)
- You don't miss your water, 1994; 2 (Box 21)
- Poems and songs, 1994-1996; 4 (Box 21)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence, poems, contracts, and printed material, 1999; 8 (Box 21)
- Correspondence, 1999; 2 (Box 21)
- Correspondence, 1999; 3 (Box 22)
- Intimate bonds, by n. a. s., undated (Box 22)
- Poems by Ronaldo Wilson, undated (Box 22)
- Poems by Sue Scavo and Rebecca Campbell, 1998 (Box 22)
- The afro taina dreams, poems by Jane Alberdeston-Coralin, 1999 (Box 22)
- Poems of others, undated; 2 (Box 22)
- Writings, including poems, prose, and Running Man, 1990s; 5 (Box 22)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence, printed material, and contracts and production schedules for Running Man, 1997-1999; 5 (Box 22)
- Correspondence, 1999; 3 (Box 23)
- Pants, by Shelley Stenhouse, 1999 (Box 23)
- "Waverly Place", undated (Box 23)
- Running Man, 2 (Box 23)
- Women of Interest, by Fred Canada, 1998 (Box 23)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence, poems of others, curriculum vitae of Cornelius Eady, and printed material, 1985-1989; 6 (Box 23)
- Unsorted papers including printed material, poems of others, 1985-1989; 3 (Box 24)
- The Hatchet's Blood: Separation, Power, and Gender in Ehing Social Life, by Marc R. Schloss, circa 1992 (Box 24)
- Poems by Shreela Ray, undated (Box 24)
- Poems by Jenny Drummey, undated (Box 24)
- "Introduction and poetry of Ruth Belasco," by C. Eady, 1990 (Box 24)
- Correspondence, 1985-1989; 3 (Box 24)
- Poems, undated (Box 24)
- Poems, Warren Wilson College, 1985 (Box 24)
- Notes, undated (Box 24)
- Victims of the Latest Dance Craze, undated (Box 24)
- Poems of others, undated (Box 24)
- Poems, undated; 3 (Box 24)
- Tenure files
  - Correspondence, 1991-1994; 2 (Box 24)
  - Requests for recommendations, 1991 (Box 24)
  - Requests to write reviews and essays, 1991 (Box 24)
  - Stony Brook business, 1991 (Box 24)
  - Letters from Xam Cartier and June Jordan, 1989-1990 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 24)
  - Poetry center business, 1991 (Box 25)
  - Reading requests and leads, 1991 (Box 25)
  - Manuscripts from students, 1990-1991 (Box 25)
  - Stony Brook foundation, 1991 (Box 25)
  - Fan letters from friends, undated (Box 25)
  - Requests to submit or use poems, 1991 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 25)
  - Writings, undated; 2 (Box 25)
  - "Reeling the Creature in" and "Traces of Light", undated; 1 (Box 37)
  - Printed material, 1987-1993; 5 (Box 25)
  - Resumes from other people, undated (Box 25)
  - Reviews and articles, 1986 (Box 25)
  - Printed material, undated; 3 (Box 25)
  - Publicity from readings, undated (Box 25)
  - Reviews of Cornelius Eady's books (Box 25)
  - "Tenure C. W.", undated (Box 25)
  - Publicity from Holt, "You Don't Miss Your Water", undated (Box 25)
- Reviews for "Brutal Imagination", undated (Box 26)
- Correspondence, 2001 (Box 26)
- Unsorted papers including printed material, correspondence, and poems of others, 1996-2001; 3 (Box 26)
- "Eyeball", 1992 (Box 36 (Oversize))
- Correspondence, 4 (Box 26)
- In Celebration of June Jordan UC Berkley, 2002 September 15; 1 (Box 37)
- "The Sour Thunder" Keith and Mendi Obadike, "The Classic Hundred Poems", 1997-2000; 2 compact discs (Box 40)
- Poems, undated (Box 26)
- Glasses case, lanyard, undated (Box 26)
- Notebook, undated (Box 26)
- Paper Armor, by Eisa Davis, after 1999 (Box 26)
- Kartunes (West Orange, NJ: Warthog Press), 1980 (Box 26)
- War- work disk, "Florida" music by Randall Eng, text by Donna, 2003; 2 compact discs (Box 40)
- Brutal Imagination, proofs, 2000; 2 (Box 26)
- Poems, undated (Box 26)
- Threshold, by Ann Beckerman, undated (Box 26)
- Textual bodies, by Percival Everett, undated (Box 26)
- Conference badge, undated (Box 27)
- A celebration of the life and work of June Jordan, 2005 (Box 27)
- Correspondence, 2000s (Box 27)
- Printed material, 2005-2010; 3 (Box 27)
- Tigertail Wordspeak, 2007; 1 (Box 40)
- Contracts, 2007 (Box 27)
- Poems, undated (Box 27)
- Photographs and publicity material, undated (Box 27)
- "Gathering ground: A 10th year celebration of The Cave Canem Workshop", undated (Box 27)
- G: An adaptation by Joe Morton of Athol Fugard's "Tsotsi", 2003 (Box 27)
- Hardheaded Weather, proofs, 2008; 3 (Box 27)
- Correspondence, 2007-2010; 5 (Box 27)
- Brutal imagination, undated (Box 27)
- Cornelius Eady at Pensacola Junior College Lyceum, promotional posters, undated (Box 36 (Oversize))
- Printed material and correspondence, 2003-2005; 5 (Box 28)
- Poems, 2004 (Box 28)
- Contracts, 2004 (Box 28)
- "Piano concert" (broadside), undated (Box 28)
- Fangs, 2004 (Box 28)
- Fangs New York City Opera Performance Excerpts, undated; 1 (Box 40)
- Poems, 2005 (Box 28)
- Correspondence, 2003-2005; 3 (Box 28)
- The war against the obvious, undated (Box 28)
- Publicity, 2007 (Box 28)
- From the tongues of brick and stone, by Brenda Cardenas, 2005 (Box 28)
- G: An adaptation by Joe Morton of Athol Fugard's "Tsotsi", 2003 (Box 28)
- At the news of your death: Three poems, by Joshua Saul Beckman (Permeable Press), 1995 (Box 28)
- Gertrude Stein invents a jump early on, 2005 (Box 28)
- Gertrude Stein invents a jump early on, 2002; 1 (Box 40)
- Writings, 2005-2010; 2 (Box 28)
- Correspondence, 2005-2010; 2 (Box 29)
- Course development and teaching workshop, presented by the Kaneb Center, undated (Box 29)
- University of Notre Dame policies (pamphlets), undated (Box 29)
- Disk, undated (Box 40)
- Cave Canem Papers
  - Computer disks, 17 3.5' floppy disks (Box 40)
  - O.B. Hardison Jr. Reading His Poetry, 2003; 1 compact disc (Box 40)
  - Employees, undated (Box 29)
  - Board meeting, 2005 October (Box 29)
  - Search director, 2006 (Box 29)
  - Board meetings, undated (Box 29)
  - "10x10", 2006 (Box 29)
  - Invitation samples, 2006 (Box 29)
  - 10th anniversary celebration, 2006 (Box 29)
  - Programs, 2005 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence from alumni, 1997-2000 (Box 29)
  - Consultants Bury, 2005 (Box 30)
  - Bylaws, undated (Box 30)
  - Invitations, most by Sarah, and glossy brochure designed by Susan Micklem, 1999-2003; 3 folders (Box 30)
  - Programs, 2010 (Box 30)
  - Cornelius clippings, 1999-2002 (Box 30)
- Unsorted papers including printed material, correpondence, and University of Notre Dame material, 2005-2010; 4 (Box 30)
- Poems of others, 2005-2010; 2 (Box 30)
- The heavy sky, by Stephanie Magdalena White (Ace Bang Up Publishing), 2007 (Box 30)
- The motherless child, circa 2007 (Box 30)
- "Gathering ground: A 10th year celebration of The Cave Canem Workshop", undated (Box 30)
- Happy birthday quilt, 2007 (Box 42 (Oversize))
- Cornelius Eady Reading UWM, 2004 April 23; 1 (Box 37)
- Correspondence, 2005-2010; 2 (Box 31)
- Promotional posters, 2005-2010 (Box 36 (Oversize))
- Printed material, meeting minutes, and correspondence, 2005-2010; 3 (Box 31)
- Correspondence, 2003-2004; 2 (Box 31)
- Publicity photographs, 2003 (Box 31)
- Correspondence, 2003-2007 (Box 31)
- Eye of water, poems by A. F. Thomas, undated (Box 31)
- Poems, 2004 (Box 31)
- Cave Canem class of 2006 (photocopy of photograph) (Box 31)
- "Paradiso" (broadside), undated (Box 31)
- Cave Canem publicity, 2007 (Box 31)
- Printed material, undated (Box 31)
- Gertrude Stein Invents a Jump Early On, 2005; 1 (Box 40)
- Cave canem letterhead, undated (Box 31)
- Correspondence, 1992, undated (Box 31)
- Unsorted papers including poems of others, undated (Box 31)
- Notebook, undated (Box 31)
- Zip disk, undated (Box 40)
- Photographs and files, 2005-2010; 3 compact discs (Box 40)
- Clippings, undated (Box 36 (Oversize))
- Printed material, correspondence, and writings, undated; 2 (Box 31)
- Poems by Suk-Hang Chin, 1992 (Box 32)
- Unsorted papers including correspondence and poems, undated; 6 (Box 32)
- Linda Pastan Poetry Center Reading, promotional poster, 1990 September 26 (Box 36 (Oversize))
- Photographs, manuscripts, and readings, 2006-2010; 9 compact discs, 1 DVD, and 1 3.5' floppy disk (Box 40)
- Squaw Valley Workshop, 1992 (Box 32)
- Friend and student manuscripts, 2004, undated (Box 32)
- Drafts of Jukebox, Running Man, and other poems, undated (Box 32)
- Clippings, undated (Box 32)
- Correspondence, 1993-1996; 2 (Box 32)
- Cornelius Eady reads his poetry at NYU top of the park, undated; 1 (Box 37)
- Alan Roth Productions; rough edit of entire Clifton/Sanchez legacy conversation, April 24, no year; 1 (Box 38)
- Reading at Kirtland Community College, 1996 March; 1 (Box 38)
- Cave Canem "rough cut edit #1", 2002 October 24; 1 (Box 38)
- Live workshop production of "You Don't Miss Water", 1995 November; 1 (Box 38)
- Live workshop production of "Brutal Imagination" at The Kitchen, 2000 October 20; 1 (Box 38)
- National Book Awards film from Working Dog Productions, 1999; 1 (Box 38)
- Cornelius Eady/ Octavia Butler reading at Donnell Library New York, 2002 February 16; 1 (Box 38)